# NICHOLAS MCMULLEN

Talent Management/HR Analytics Leader

# SUMMARY

People-driven professional with a variety of HCM analytics, human resources, talent management, system administration, compensation administration/strategy, and statistical computing experience. Experience with multiple HR system implementations, including compensation platform (CompAnalyst), LXP, and ATS. Strong desire to enter into a people operations role and contribute both analytical and people-driven efficiencies throughout all levels of the organization.

# CORE SKILLS

- Compensation administration (base & variable incentive)
- Talent management (succession planning, talent assessments)
- Talent onboarding
- Organizational change management
- Process improvement
- Project management (technical & organizational change)
- Managerial experience
- HR software system implementation
- UltiPro HRIS
- iCIMS ATS (lead administrator)
- RStudio
- Tableau Desktop
- IBM Cognos Analytics
- Cornerstone LMS (administrator experience)

# CONTACT

Mobile: (928) 951-4369

**Email**: nicholasgmcmullen@gmail.com **Website**: nickmcmullen.github.io

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-mcmullen/

Location: Phoenix, Arizona

# EXPERIENCE

### Manager, People Systems & Analytics

#### Alliance Residential Company | February 2020 - Present

- Administer a variety of base & variable compensation plans (sales, executive)
- Technical lead on compensation committee, compensation consultation
- Oversee operation, maintenance, improvement of all people systems
- Lead change management efforts for people ops technology initiatives
- Consult with top executives using analytics to inform people ops decisions

#### **Business Data Analyst**

#### Alliance Residential Company | January 2020 - February 2020

- Administer/improve quarterly bonus variable pay plan
- Own all organizational data science initiatives
- Conduct statistical analyses of performance/HR/compensation data

#### **Talent Analytics Manager**

#### Alliance Residential Company | August 2018 - January 2020

- Oversee Talent Coordinator team (onboarding function)
- Company-wide system administrator for ATS (iCIMS)
- Consult with top executives on base pay strategy, market job mappings
- Act as main point of contact for all vendors of Talent Management dept.
- Support organizational recruiting function

#### Learning Manager

#### Alliance Residential Company | May 2018 - August 2018

- Manage all analytics and data initiatives for training department
- System administrator for company LMS (Cornerstone)
- Assess training effectiveness and ROI (in-person & virtual)

# EDUCATION

#### Macalester College

B.A. Applied Mathematics & Statistics, magna cum laude

August 2014 - May 2018

# CERTIFICATIONS

#### **Tableau Software**

Desktop Certified Associate | October 2019 - October 2021

#### **Dale Carnegie Training**

Certified in Leading Accountable Engagement | October 2019

# ORGANIZATIONS/COMMITTEES

**Certified Performance Pay Committee** 

Deer Valley Unified School District | January 2020 - Present

WorldatWork Total Rewards Association

Member | October 2019 - Present